Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Late 19th Century Photographic Materials MC.230
New York University Archives
- Series III. Glass Plate Negative Fragments, 1872-1879, undated; 2.50 Linear Feet in 1 card box, 3 oversize flat boxes, and 6 custom boxes.
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14839 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14840 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14841 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14842 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14843 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14844 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14845 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14846 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14847 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14848 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14849 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14851 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Segments of Solar Disk, undated; cuid14852 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Fragment (Mended), undated; cuid14853 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14854 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14855 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14856 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Distribution of Stars of Type V, undated; cuid14857 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14858 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14899 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14859 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14860 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14861 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14900 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14901 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14862 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14863 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Solar Spectrum?, undated; cuid14865 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Box of Fragments, undated; cuid14866 (Box 26)
- Series IV. Henry Draper-Related Observatories and Laboratories Images, 1870s-1898, undated; 2 Linear Feet in 6 custom boxes.
  This series contains images of Henry Draper's lab and observatory in Hastings-on-Hudson, circa 1870s-1880s. This series also includes images from the 1890s related to The Henry Draper Memorial which was established by his widow and involved the transfer of a collection of Draper's instruments and telescopes to Harvard College Observatory. Image subjects include interiors, exteriors, people working in the lab, equipment, and other machinery.
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory Interior with Telescope, circa 1870s-1882; cuid14579 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory Interior with Telescope, circa 1870s-1882; cuid14576 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Interior View of Draper's Physical Laboratory Behind His Wooster Street Home, NYC, circa 1870s-1882; cuid14810 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Draper's Laboratory Interior -- Man Using Weights and Scales, circa 1870s-1882; cuid14565 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Draper's Laboratory Interior -- Man Using Weights and Scales, circa 1870s-1882; cuid14566 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Draper's Laboratory Interior with Man Working on Machine, circa 1870s-1882; cuid14581 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Harvard College Observatory Grounds and Buildings, circa 1896; cuid14559 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Draper's Clark Refractor Installed at Harvard College Observatory, circa 1896; cuid14563 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Harvard College Observatory Grounds and Buildings, circa 1896-1898; cuid14833 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Draper Domes and Telescope, View from South of Observatory at Harvard College, 1897; cuid14875 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - 8" Draper Camera at the Harvard College Observatory, circa 1898; cuid14562 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Naval Observatory -- Three Men Standing on a Tree-Lined Driveway, undated; cuid14560 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Naval Observatory -- Buildings and Yard Construction, undated; cuid14561 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Outdoor Setting with Buildings, Driveway, Two Men, undated; cuid14835 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Draper's Laboratory Equipment, undated; cuid14567 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Draper's Laboratory Equipment, undated; cuid14568 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Draper's Laboratory Equipment -- Schematic, undated; cuid14569 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Draper's Laboratory Equipment -- Large Glass Testing Tubes, undated; cuid14570 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Heliostat at Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory, undated; cuid14577 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Interior with Pipes and Valves, undated; cuid14578 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory, undated; cuid14571 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory, undated; cuid14572 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory, undated; cuid14573 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory (Blank), undated; cuid14574 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory (Blank), undated; cuid14575 (Box 34, Folder 19)
- Series V. D.W. Hering X-Ray Images, circa 1885-1902; 1 linear foot in 1 custom box.
  This series contains seven x-ray images, circa 1885-1902, taken by D.W. Hering, professor of physics at New York University beginning in 1885 and known for his early work in Roentgen X-rays.
  - X-Ray, circa 1885-1902; cuid14543 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - X-Ray, circa 1885-1902; cuid14544 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - X-Ray of Six Month Old Child, circa 1885-1902; cuid14545 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - X-Ray of Six Month Old Child, circa 1885-1902; cuid14547 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - X-Ray of Bones, circa 1885-1902; cuid14546 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - X-Ray of Bones, circa 1885-1902; cuid14548 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - X-Ray of Bones, circa 1885-1902; cuid14549 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Series VI. NYU Campus, Students, and Related Images, 1890s-1926, undated; 5 Linear Feet in 4 custom boxes and 1 oversize flat box.
  This series contains images dating from the 1890s of New York University's University Heights campus, buildings, and student life, as well as street views of the surrounding neighborhood. Images of the NYU exhibition at the 1893 World's Columbian Exposition in Chicago taken by C.L. Bristol are also in this series.
  - Scale Model Display of NYU Campus, 1890s; cuid14585 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - NYU Campus, 1890s; cuid14587 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - NYU Campus, 1890s; cuid14588 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - NYU Campus, 1890s; cuid14589 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Scale Model of NYU Campus in Glass Display Case, 1890s; cuid14594 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Scale Model Display of NYU Campus, 1890s; cuid14595 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - NYU Campus in the Snow, 1890s; cuid14596 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - NYU Campus, 1890s; cuid14597 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - NYU Campus in the Snow, 1890s; cuid14598 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - NYU Campus in the Snow, circa 1890s; cuid14590 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - NYU Exhibit at World's Columbian Exposition, Chicago, 1893; cuid14582 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - NYU Exhibit at World's Columbian Exposition, Chicago, 1893; cuid14583 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - NYU Exhibit at World's Columbian Exposition, Chicago, 1893; cuid14584 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - NYU Exhibit at World's Columbian Exposition, Chicago, 1893; cuid14591 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - NYU Exhibit at World's Columbian Exposition, Chicago, 1893; cuid14592 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - NYU Exhibit at World's Columbian Exposition, Chicago, 1893; cuid14593 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - NYU Main Building, 1894; cuid14599 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - NYU Main Building in Washington Square Campus, 1894; cuid14600 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - University Heights Biological Lab, circa 1895; cuid14610 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Students in Survey Class -- University Heights Grounds, circa 1895; cuid14609 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Students with Engineering Survey Equipment, circa 1895; cuid14611 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Student Life -- Man Sitting on Motorcycle, circa 1910s; cuid14626 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Student Life -- Basketball Team and Coach, 1912-1913; cuid14620 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Students on Steps Outside Gould Memorial Library During Chapel Hour, from page 88 of the 1914 Violet, 1913; cuid14612 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Class Day at the Heights Campus, circa 1913; cuid14613 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Chemistry Lab, from page 228 of the 1914 Violet, 1913; cuid14614 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Founders Monument at University Heights Campus, 1920; cuid14817 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Guggenheim Lab Building Ironwork Skeleton, 9 July 1926; cuid14618 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Group of Men, undated; cuid14601 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Heights Neighborhood -- New Central Bridge, Haven River and 155th, undated; cuid14602 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Heights Neighborhood -- Valley at Harlem, undated; cuid14603 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Heights Neighborhood -- Railroad, Station, and Street Scene, undated; cuid14604 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Heights Neighborhood -- New Government Ship Canal Connecting Harlem and Hudson Rivers, circa 1895; cuid14605 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Heights Neighborhood -- Bridge Over River with Kessell's Manhattan Par(lor?) and Lion Brewery, undated; cuid14606 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Heights Neighborhood -- Bridge Construction with Workmen in Foreground, undated; cuid14607 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Heights Neighborhood -- Horse and Carriage on Bridge, undated; cuid14608 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - NYU Campus, undated; cuid14625 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Student Life -- Interior with Group of Men and Women, undated; cuid14615 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Student Life -- Group Portrait of Men, undated; cuid14616 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Student Life -- Gymnasium Interior with Men and Women Dancing, undated; cuid14617 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Student Life -- Group Portrait of Women and Men Sitting on Porch Steps, undated; cuid14619 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Student Life -- Group Portrait of Women and Men Sitting on Porch Steps, undated; cuid14622 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Student Life -- Long Line of Men on Campus, undated; cuid14621 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Student Life -- Group Portrait of Fraternity Brothers, undated; cuid14623 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Student Life -- Group Portrait of Fraternity Brothers, undated; cuid14628 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Student Life -- Men Walking in Front of Fraternity House, undated; cuid14624 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Student Life -- Fraternity House, undated; cuid14630 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Student Life -- Two Football Players in Uniform on Field, undated; cuid14627 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Student Life -- Baseball Player in Uniform, undated; cuid14629 (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Series VII. Lecture Presentation Support Images, 1863-1900, undated; 1 linear foot in 3 custom boxes.
  This series contains lantern slides used for various educational presentations and lectures. Subjects include astrophotography images of the moon dating from 1863 to 1864; early solar spectrum images from the 1860s-1890s; radiographic images taken by D.W. Hering and C.L. Bristol; and laboratory spectrum with various elements. This series also contains stock illustrations of landscapes, city streets, mountains, portrait of James Prescott Joule, images of ancient art; and views of building ruins in Johnstown after a catastrophic event.
  - Moon, 3 August 1863; cuid14700 (Box 32, Folder 69)
  - Moon, 3 August 1863; cuid14705 (Box 32, Folder 74)
  - Moon, 3 August 1863; cuid14704 (Box 32, Folder 73)
  - Moon, 4 August 1863; cuid14698 (Box 32, Folder 67)
  - Moon, 27 August 1863; cuid14694 (Box 32, Folder 63)
  - Moon, 27 August 1863; cuid14706 (Box 32, Folder 75)
  - Moon, 28 August 1863; cuid14697 (Box 32, Folder 66)
  - Moon, 30 August 1863; cuid14702 (Box 32, Folder 71)
  - Moon, 30 August 1863; cuid14708 (Box 32, Folder 77)
  - Moon, 30 August 1863; cuid14703 (Box 32, Folder 72)
  - Moon, 2 September 1863; cuid14714 (Box 32, Folder 83)
  - Moon, 12 June 1864; cuid14716 (Box 32, Folder 85)
  - Moon, 15 June 1864; cuid14701 (Box 32, Folder 70)
  - Moon, 16 June 1864; cuid14713 (Box 32, Folder 82)
  - Moon, 19 June 1864; cuid14699 (Box 32, Folder 68)
  - Moon, 21 June 1864; cuid14712 (Box 32, Folder 81)
  - Moon, 22 June 1864; cuid14715 (Box 32, Folder 84)
  - Moon, 22 June 1864; cuid14717 (Box 32, Folder 86)
  - Moon, 22 June 1864; cuid14718 (Box 32, Folder 87)
  - Moon, 22 June 1864; cuid14719 (Box 32, Folder 88)
  - Moon, 23 June 1864; cuid14720 (Box 32, Folder 89)
  - Moon, 25 June 1864; cuid14723 (Box 32, Folder 92)
  - Moon, 25 August 1864; cuid14711 (Box 32, Folder 80)
  - Moon, August 1864; cuid14721 (Box 32, Folder 90)
  - Moon, August-September 1864; cuid14722 (Box 32, Folder 91)
  - Moon, August-September 1864; cuid14726 (Box 32, Folder 95)
  - Moon, 14 September 1864; cuid14724 (Box 32, Folder 93)
  - Moon, 16 September 1864; cuid14695 (Box 32, Folder 64)
  - Moon, 17 September 1864; cuid14725 (Box 32, Folder 94)
  - Moon, 17 September 1864; cuid14727 (Box 32, Folder 96)
  - Moon, 13 October 1864; cuid14709 (Box 32, Folder 78)
  - Moon, 15 October 1864; cuid14696 (Box 32, Folder 65)
  - Moon, 15 October 1864; cuid14710 (Box 32, Folder 79)
  - Moon, 18 October 1864; cuid14707 (Box 32, Folder 76)
  - Colored Spectra of a Star, 18 February 1869; cuid14729 (Box 32, Folder 98)
  - Early Solar Spectrum, circa 1870; cuid14688 (Box 31, Folder 57)
  - Early Solar Spectrum, circa 1870; cuid14689 (Box 31, Folder 58)
  - Laboratory Spectrum of CuNO5, circa 1870; cuid14690 (Box 31, Folder 59)
  - Laboratory Spectrum of Tin and Mercury, circa 1870; cuid14691 (Box 31, Folder 60)
  - Laboratory Spectrum of Magnesium, circa 1870; cuid14692 (Box 31, Folder 61)
  - Laboratory Spectrum of Platinum, circa 1870; cuid14693 (Box 31, Folder 62)
  - Solar Spectra, 1873; cuid14755 (Box 32, Folder 124)
  - Solar Spectra, 1873; cuid14756 (Box 32, Folder 125)
  - Solar Spectra, 1873; cuid14757 (Box 32, Folder 126)
  - Solar Spectra, 1873; cuid14758 (Box 32, Folder 127)
  - Nova Normae, 1889-1893; cuid14781 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Nova Aurigae, 16 February 1890 - 17 December 1891; cuid14775 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Nova Normae, 20 June - 10 July 1893; cuid14782 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Radiograph of Frog with Piece of Lead in Thorax -- By D.W. Hering and C.L. Bristol, February 1896; cuid14667 (Box 31, Folder 36)
  - Radiograph of Lead Pencil, Steel Calipers, Fountain Pen -- By D.W. Hering and C.L. Bristol, 1896; cuid14668 (Box 31, Folder 37)
  - Radiograph of Clam Shell and Other Items -- By D.W. Hering and C.L. Bristol, February 1896; cuid14669 (Box 31, Folder 38)
  - Radiograph of Disc of Lead with Sheet of Celluloid -- By D.W. Hering and C.L. Bristol, February 1896; cuid14670 (Box 31, Folder 39)
  - Radiograph of Steel Gauge in Morocco Case and Metal Badge in Round Wooden Box -- By D.W. Hering and C.L. Bristol, February 1896; cuid14671 (Box 31, Folder 40)
  - Radiograph of Steel Gauge in Morocco Case and Other Objects -- By D.W. Hering, 1896; cuid14672 (Box 31, Folder 41)
  - Radiograph of Knife, Small Carbon Pencil, Chalk, Crayon, and Dropper -- By D.W. Hering and C.L. Bristol, February 1896; cuid14673 (Box 31, Folder 42)
  - Radiograph of Steel Gauge in Morocco Case and Other Objects -- By D.W. Hering, 29 February 1896; cuid14675 (Box 31, Folder 44)
  - Radiograph of Steel Calipers Enclosed in Wooden Box and Keys Outside of Box -- By D.W. Hering, February 1896; cuid14677 (Box 31, Folder 46)
  - Radiograph of Two Stripes of Sheet Lead -- By D.W. Hering and C.L. Bristol, February 1896; cuid14676 (Box 31, Folder 45)
  - Radiograph of Six Month Old Child -- By D.W. Hering and C.L. Bristol, 1896; cuid14678 (Box 31, Folder 47)
  - Radiograph of a Leg -- By D.W. Hering and C.L. Bristol, 1896; cuid14679 (Box 31, Folder 48)
  - X-ray Machine at NYU, 1896; cuid14681 (Box 31, Folder 50)
  - Showing the Taking of Radiograph at NYU Laboratory -- By D.W. Hering, February 1896; cuid14680 (Box 31, Folder 49)
  - Pine Hill Highway Bridge -- By D.W. Hering, 1897; cuid14656 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Radiograph of Photographic Action of Radium A Over Circular Gauge and Radium B Over Rectangular Gauge -- By D.W. Hering, 29-30 May 1900; cuid14674 (Box 31, Folder 43)
  - Moon -- Possible Copy of Draper's Original, 15 June, undated; cuid14634 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Moon -- Possible Copy of Draper's Original, 22 June, undated; cuid14637 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Moon, undated; cuid14635 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Moon, undated; cuid14636 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Moon, undated; cuid14737 (Box 32, Folder 106)
  - Colored Spectra, undated; cuid14728 (Box 32, Folder 97)
  - Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid14632 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Spectrum, undated; cuid14771 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14773 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid14633 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Early Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid14682 (Box 31, Folder 51)
  - Early Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid14683 (Box 31, Folder 52)
  - Early Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid14684 (Box 31, Folder 53)
  - Early Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid14685 (Box 31, Folder 54)
  - Early Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid14686 (Box 31, Folder 55)
  - Early Solar Spectrum, undated; cuid14687 (Box 31, Folder 56)
  - Spectra of Alpha Canis Majoris, Alpha Canis Minoris, and Alpha Aurigae, undated; cuid14784 (Box 33, Folder 26)
    Sample sent to Mrs. Draper December 12 1897. Four prisms enlarged about thrice.
  - Spectra of Alpha Lyrae, Alpha Cygni, and Alpha Bootis, undated; cuid14785 (Box 33, Folder 27)
    Sample sent to Mrs. Draper December 12 1897.
  - Spectra of Beta Persei and Beta Lyrae, undated; cuid14786 (Box 33, Folder 28)
    Sample sent to Mrs. Draper December 12 1897. Spectra of Beta Persei and Beta Lyrae at full light time and at minimum. The difference in width of the lines. The disappearance of 1 line at minimum and the overlapping of the ends of the spectra may be real phenomena and require further study. A number of plates taken last night will probably settle these points. The other spectra represent the variables Beta Lyrae and Omicron Ceti. The differences in these types of variables is well shown by these spectra. One prism (?) enlarged three times.
  - Spectra of Alpha Cassiopeii, P. Cygni, and H.P. 1311, undated; cuid14787 (Box 33, Folder 29)
    Samples sent to Mrs. Draper December 23 1889.
  - Sun, undated; cuid14730 (Box 32, Folder 99)
  - Sun, undated; cuid14731 (Box 32, Folder 100)
  - Sun, undated; cuid14732 (Box 32, Folder 101)
  - Sun, undated; cuid14733 (Box 32, Folder 102)
  - Solar Disk, undated; cuid14734 (Box 32, Folder 103)
  - Solar Disk, undated; cuid14735 (Box 32, Folder 104)
  - Solar Disk, undated; cuid14738 (Box 32, Folder 107)
  - Solar Disk D.T.G., undated; cuid14739 (Box 32, Folder 108)
  - Solar Disk, undated; cuid14740 (Box 32, Folder 109)
  - Solar Disk, undated; cuid14741 (Box 32, Folder 110)
  - Solar Disk, undated; cuid14742 (Box 32, Folder 111)
  - Solar Image, undated; cuid14743 (Box 32, Folder 112)
  - Sunspots, undated; cuid14749 (Box 32, Folder 118)
  - Sunspots, undated; cuid14750 (Box 32, Folder 119)
  - "Painted" Spectrum, undated; cuid14744 (Box 32, Folder 113)
  - "Painted" Spectra, undated; cuid14746 (Box 32, Folder 115)
  - "Painted" Spectra, undated; cuid14747 (Box 32, Folder 116)
  - "Painted" Spectra, undated; cuid14748 (Box 32, Folder 117)
  - Diagram -- Mars-Schiaparelli, undated; cuid14638 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Diagram -- Parallax, undated; cuid14639 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Diagram Chart -- Coincidence of the Spectrum of Iron with 65 of the Fraunhofer Lines, undated; cuid14640 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Astronomy, undated; cuid14641 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Telescope, undated; cuid14642 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Living Room, undated; cuid14643 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Telescope in Observatory, undated; cuid14644 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Arequipa Station Exterior, undated; cuid14645 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Arequipa Station Exterior, undated; cuid14646 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Illustration -- Hot Springs, Isle Ngau, undated; cuid14647 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Illustration -- Jungle Landscape, undated; cuid14648 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Illustration -- Siberian Landscape, undated; cuid14649 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Cityscape, undated; cuid14650 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Cityscape with Snow, undated; cuid14651 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Cityscape with Snow, undated; cuid14652 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Landscape with Buildings, undated; cuid14653 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Mountain Range, undated; cuid14654 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Bridge over a River, undated; cuid14655 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Johnstown Ruins of City -- Smoking Buildings, undated; cuid14657 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Johnstown Central View -- Ruins of Houses, undated; cuid14658 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Johnstown Ruins -- Ottenad Furniture Company Building at Broadway and Soulard, undated; cuid14659 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Johnstown Ruins -- Fourth Street and Choteau Avenue, undated; cuid14660 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Niagara Falls -- American Side, undated; cuid14661 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Covered Bridge with Horse and Buggy, undated; cuid14662 (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Illustration -- Ideal Geological Landcape, Forest of Coal Period, undated; cuid14663 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - Insect Specimens, undated; cuid14664 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Nerves, undated; cuid14665 (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - Room's Reflection on a Sphere, undated; cuid14666 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - Pair of Optical Slits, undated; cuid14751 (Box 32, Folder 120)
  - Pair of Optical Slits, undated; cuid14752 (Box 32, Folder 121)
  - Wavelength Scale, undated; cuid14753 (Box 32, Folder 122)
  - Mask with Set of Slits, undated; cuid14754 (Box 32, Folder 123)
  - James Prescott Joule Portrait, undated; cuid14759 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Diagram -- James Prescott Joule's Early Apparatus, undated; cuid14760 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Diagram -- James Prescott Joule's Later Apparatus, undated; cuid14761 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Diagram -- Rowland's Apparatus, undated; cuid14762 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Illustration -- Two Cats on a Roof and the Moon, undated; cuid14763 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14764 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14765 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14766 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14768 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14769 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14770 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Mg with Plate of Glass in Rays, undated; cuid14767 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Chart -- Pleicedes Showing Nebula Around Stars Taken with 8 inch Telescope, undated; cuid14772 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Bl. Lines Argus, undated; cuid14774 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - 434, undated; cuid14776 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Spetra -- Nova Normae and Nova Aurigae, undated; cuid14777 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - New Variable in Scorpius, undated; cuid14778 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Cluster in Centauri, undated; cuid14779 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - New Variable in Scorpius, 28 May - 13 July 18--; cuid14780 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - The Southern Cross, undated; cuid14783 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14788 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14789 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14790 (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14791 (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14792 (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14793 (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14794 (Box 33, Folder 36)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14795 (Box 33, Folder 37)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14796 (Box 33, Folder 38)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14797 (Box 33, Folder 39)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14798 (Box 33, Folder 40)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14799 (Box 33, Folder 41)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14800 (Box 33, Folder 42)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14801 (Box 33, Folder 43)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14802 (Box 33, Folder 44)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14803 (Box 33, Folder 45)
  - Ancient Art Images, undated; cuid14804 (Box 33, Folder 46)